Register of the Ferenc Koszorus writings, 1954-1970
Hoover Institution Archives
Ferenc Koszorus writings,
1954-1970
75055
Koszorus, Ferenc, 1899-1974
1 manuscript box (0.4 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Relates to Hungarian, German, Soviet, and international military strategy during World Wars I and II. Includes a letter and notes from F. Koszorus to General Omar Bradley, 1953.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
Biographical/Historical Note
Colonel, Hungarian army.
Access Points
World War, 1914-1918.; World War, 1939-1945.; Hungary.; Hungary--Military policy.; Bradley, Omar Nelson, 1893-1981.
Container List
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1953 (Box 1)
  - Bradley, Omar, 1953. Includes an analysis of strategies employed in modern warfare.
- WRITINGS, 1954-1970
  - Addenda to the Development of Hungary's Fate to It's Present State (in Hungarian) undated
  - Dominating Strategic Position of the Carpathian Basin As Bastion of Western Europe, undated
  - Future Wars and Atomic Weapons (in Hungarian), English translation, Washington D. C., August 25, 1954
  - The Hungarian Tragedy of World War II in the Light of Justice (in Hungarian), Washington D. C., March 10, 1963
  - Initial Operations of the 3rd Army (in Hungarian), Washington D. C., January 26, 1968
  - The Lakatas Government (in Hungarian), undated
  - 1943-44 - Military Balance (in Hungarian), undated
  - Politics and Military Strategy (in Hungarian), undated
  - The Relationship Between Hitlerian Ideology and the Hungarian Soldier - An Answer to Postwar German Military Literature (in Hungarian), in duplicate, German translation, Washington D. C., June 15, 1963
  - The Roots of the Troubles (in Hungarian), English translation, undated
  - Thoughts on Trianon (in Hungarian), Washington D. C., November 29, 1970
  - The Thwarting of the First Nazi Attempt to Seize Power by Force in Budapest on July 6, 1944, Washington D. C., November 17, 1961
- INCREMENT February 1977
  - The Roots of the Troubles, undated